



Paterno BALDOMAR CAD Operator

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

BIM/CAD Designer for almost 3 decades, experienced in architectural design, details, documentation and coordination with proficiency in Revit Architecture (BIM) and AutoCAD (CAD) software application. He is currently working in VSL Civil Works Philippine Branch which is specialized in viaduct and bridge post-tensioning and has been closely involved in the construction of North South Commuter Rail (NSCR) project. Prior to that, he worked as BIM Designer in Kewaunee Labway Asia Pte. Ltd., he implemented the migration and transition of company standard from AutoCAD to Revit (BIM). Creating Revit families from AutoCAD blocks, organizing Revit project browser, setting up view templates, and schedule templates. His proficiency in BIM technology enhanced productivity and efficiency in project implementation and execution.

SKILLS

Skills:

- Proficient in AutoCAD software
- Proficient in Revit Architecture (BIM)
- Proficient in Microsoft office

Languages:

Filipino Language: Native LanguageEnglish Language: Advanced

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

- Bachelor of Science in Architecture – Technological Institute of the Philippines, Manila, Philippines (June 1986 – March 1991)

PERSONAL DETAILS

- Marital Status: Married
- Spouse Name: Cecilia Dorado Baldomar
- Number of Dependents (children): 3
 - Shamir Israel Dorado Baldomar
 - Genesis King Dorado Baldomar
 - Kyla Mary Dorado Baldomar
- Open for mobility: Yes

Paterno BALDOMAR CAD Operator

WORK EXPERIENCES / KEY POSITIONS

CAD Operator, NSCR CP01 Project, Technical Department/VSL Civil Works Philippine Branch, Philippines September 2000 - Present

Length of Service: 3 years plus

North South Commuter Rail Project (NSCR), Valenzuela - Malolos Section.

Technical Department, Prepare the necessary requirements for viaduct superstructures shop drawing submission.

- Plotting viaducts span coordinates.
- Segment concrete shop drawing details.
- Pre-cast tendon arrangement shop drawing details.
- Segment rebar shop drawing details.
- Schedule of rebar and bar bending shop drawing details.

BIM Designer, Kewaunee Labway Asia Pte Ltd, Singapore

June 1999 – March 2020

Length of Service: 20 years and 9 months

Laboratory Furniture Designer

Responsible in generation and maintenance of project from initial proposal, tender drawing, shop drawing and final as built drawing using Revit & AutoCAD software in adherence to BIM standard and development procedure. Generate schedule of material for quotation and order processing. Coordinate & collaborate with other trades & discipline to resolve discrepancies and interfacing issues. Prepare detailed drawing to facilitate coordination with relevant stake holder. Generation of non-standard Revit parametric families when necessary.

CAD Designer, Chua Ka Seng & Partners Chartered Architect, Singapore April 1996 – April 1999 Length of Service: 3 years Architectural Designer

Involved in project development on different stages: 1.) Conceptual Design Phase – presentation of design concept which comprises of feasibility study, tabulation of areas for plot ratio requirements on building coverage and open space, and drawing presentation such as plans, elevations, sections, perspective drawings, graphics and images, 2.) Design Development Phase – production of complete working drawings which includes the preparation of necessary architectural plans and miscellaneous detail drawing for construction. Coordination with other consultants such as Structural, Mechanical and Electrical. 3.) Construction Phase – involved in preparation of addendum drawings as per latest site condition. Check and coordinate shop drawing submitted by the building contractor for approval.



Paterno BALDOMAR CAD Operator

CAD Designer, Al-Id Engineering Consultants, K.S.A. January 1994 – January 1996 Length of Service: 2 years Architectural Designer

Preparation of schematic drawing for owner and building official's approval. Production of complete working drawing of the approved plan. Coordinate Architectural drawing with other Engineering disciplines such as Structural, Mechanical and Electrical.

Assistant Job Captain, W.V.Coscolluela & Associates, Philippines Dec. 1991 – Jan 1994 Length of Service: 2 years and 1 months Architectural Drafter

Assist in production of complete working drawing as per client approved design. Assist in preparation of all necessary information for coordination with other engineering disciplines. Prepare technical and general specification for Job Captain's approval. Conduct site inspection. Check shop drawing submitted by the contractor for approval. Check and approved samples of building material as per specification or approved equal. Responsible for filing of incoming and outgoing documents, such as transmittal letters, fax, minutes of meeting.

